Hal?
We settled on this hour.
Why are you?
Trespassing,
disturbing the throne—
You know what you're in for?
Sire.
I come at Chancellor Xu's bidding,
to present tea.
I've walked
on thin ice all the way,
hoping you would taste it.
But the moment I saw you,
I lost my wits,
and slipped into the water.
I meant no offense.
Sire.
Ruomei is no wanton woman.
It is only…
I have long admired you.
What is that scent?
Was that Chancellor Xu, too?
To serve you in the palace
has been my dearest wish.
The Chancellor saw
my devotion to you.
That's why he lent a hand.
Madness.
Please, sire,
take pity on my heart,
and let me stay by your side.
I shall spare you just this once.
Now, out of my sight.
Sire.
Coming here tonight
was already beyond all bounds.
If I was cast out now
in this state,
rumours will fly.
My reputation would be ruined,
and I would be undone.
When you hatched this scheme,
you should've
seen it coming.
Get out.
Then I must die for my offense.
If you must die,
get as far away as you can.
Steward You.
Sire... Sire!
Please, think twice.
Are you in league with the Chancellor
against me as well?
Calm yourself, sire.
It's all for
your good.
Enough.
Sire.
Sire!
Sire...
Sire.
The rain is pouring harder.
We'd better head back.
How dare you lay hands upon
an official!
Do not pull that rank on us.
You are in our hands now.
You do as we say.
I hear Lady Meng
is the Emperor's sweetheart.
Tonight, we are the emperors.
One more step
and you are damn dead meat.
You freaking hit me? You mad dog!
Feisty.
Let go!
Let us see how long
you can keep that up.
Scums!
Let go!
Get off me!
Come on, my lady.
Look,
I like them
with fire.
They say you'd spend your life
serving the people.
Get off me!
Now tonight,
attend to the two of us
like a servant.
Come on, sweetie.
Brother.
You alright?
Don't you dare!
Hold her.
Keep running, shall we?
Go ahead.
W-Witchcraft!
Lady Meng!
My lady?
What happened?
Qing.
Leave it.
Let's get back.
Your Majesty!
Something's up.
Lady Meng
was attacked on her way
back to the Bureau.
Sire.
Zhili says
Lady Meng will not see anyone.
Commandant.
Find that villain for me,
even if you had to
tear the city apart.
Miss!
Miss.
You haven't
slept a wink tending for your father.
You must be exhausted.
Let me handle the tea
and medicine.
Xi'er.
He has been
in a daze lately.
He can't even keep down his meds.
I got a new prescription
from a famed healer.
I must find a way
to get it into him.
Miss...
Oh, hello, Miss Yan.
Congratulations.
A match made in heaven.
Xi'er.
What's this supposed to be?
Mr. Yan. Sir.
Sir.
Betrothal gifts from the Songs.
A whole lot of them.
I have been bed-ridden for weeks.
The sight of this
suddenly got me up and about.
The master was right.
A wedding charm works wonders.
Father.
Do you know how worried I was?
I left my business behind, rushing
all the way home.
Yet you're faking illness to trap me into marriage!
You left me no choice!
Shazhou's already
beneath you, isn't it?
You had to follow Meng Tinghui to the capital.
I didn't
go there just for Tinghui.
I have my own ambitions.
What ambitions?
Her reputation
for open manslaughter
has reached as far as Shazhou.
If you keep running with her,
who will marry you?
Calm down, my lord.
I heard the branch in the capital,
is under Meng Tinghui's name.
It's thriving.
Though Fuzhi
deals with men all day,
she does
know her business inside out.
Meng Tinghui can
soar all she wants,
but we want none of it.
And I won't have my daughter out there
going up and down hawking.
What an eyesore!
Father.
You'd taught me
to read ledgers when I was little,
saying I had a head for business.
Now I've made Bofeng
a well-run establishment,
and expanded it.
What's wrong with all that?
I'm not after high approbation,
but you've done me no justice.
Fuzhi...
What are you up to now?
Fuzhi.
Your father means well.
Look,
the gifts are accepted.
Do not make this hard on him.
We're well acquainted with the Songs.
They are wealthy,
and have been the best partner ever.
Abreast of your marriage,
our businesses
will merge as one.
Isn't it a safer bet than
floundering on your own out there?
Just admit it.
The Songs must have been
slipping you bribes
to keep their business intact.
That's why you've been
urging Father to marry me off.
Such accusations!
Father,
she is crazy about
marrying me off,
so that she can
take over our estate,
and pass my dowry
to her own son.
And you...
Have you ever
stood by me for just one second?
If Mother were here,
she'd never
ask me to be who I'm not.
Fuzhi...
- Father!
- My dear.
I go to all these lengths just so
Fuzhi can
settle down at a proper age,
and bring you joy in your retirement.
Who'd have thought she'd think so ill of me!
All these years,
I have run this household,
worked myself to the bone.
I deserve better than her whining!
Well, forget it.
Father!
We should just call it off.
Damn, we should!
I will not marry. I mean every word of it.
Stop her now!
Take Fuzhi back to her room.
You stand guard outside.
Without my word,
she does not set one foot out.
How long am I
going to stay locked up?
Until the day you marry.
Sir, Ma'am, might we give it
a second thought?
If Fuzhi is dead set against this,
maybe we should...
Delay breeds trouble.
Stick to the plan. On the date they chose.
The sooner, the better.
It is just three days away.
So be it.
Three days hence, she marries.
Let us see
without Meng Tinghui,
who will come to your aid.
Lock her up.
Let me go.
Sir.
What brings you here?
I heard about Meng Tinghui.
I imagined you must be terrified.
They say you haven't been home for nights,
buried in files at the Bureau,
hunting for those brigands.
I just... cannot believe it.
A woman as integral as her
should suffer such a fate!
I hate those villains.
I wish they're gutted
could strike them dead.
Men like that
shall not pass on his life,
turning in hell.
You grow to be
just like Meng—
harsh-tongued.
Just saying it out loud
what everyone is thinking.
To use such vile methods
against a defenseless person
is contemptible.
Now
she has shut herself away,
rejecting any visitor.
What if she...
hurt herself in there?
Thank heaven you are safe.
Zhili.
I need your opinion on this:
Chancellor Xu has always
spoken ill of Meng.
With her reputation tarnished,
he will blow this out of proportion
to undermine the Bureau.
Suppose
she loses her position at some point.
I've been thinking I'd
recommend you to His Majesty
to take her place.
You mean
for me to replace Tinghui?
I cannot.
Do you know
how she suffers at this moment?
Just to think of it
cuts me to the heart.
This is a most horrible thought,
when she is at her lowest.
My dear.
I feel extremely sorry for her pain.
But I've always believed
the Bureau needs a woman of
your virtue and flair
to uphold its integrity.
You'll make
a better chief than she does.
Now that she has fallen,
you've been shouldering it all.
It pains me to see it.
I want to help preserve
what you and His Majesty
have so painstakingly built.
When Tinghui first took charge,
voices were everywhere
saying a woman could not lead.
Now she is in dire straits,
and you ask me to seize her power?
How is that preserving anything?
You always see reason.
How come you fail to
understand it now?
If Chancellor Xu doesn't move against her,
so much the better.
But what if he does?
The Bureau exists only
because Tinghui is in it.
If you truly wish to help me,
then stand firmly with me,
whatever Xu's move is.
I will share Tinghui's fate.
This office...
I can do without.
I am useless, My Lady.
I could not protect you.
Sire.
Will you teach me how to defend myself?
Come on in. This way.
Congratulations.
And to you.
Please, this way.
Here, groom.
Here, bride.
Please don't make this difficult.
I'm only doing what I am paid to do.
Father.
Mother.
I shall take Fuzhi home now.
Very well.
Come, Fuzhi.
Get off me.
A father
faking illness to sell his daughter;
a mother stabbing her in the back.
You've thrown me to the wolves.
Fuzhi, don't be dramatic,
not on this occasion.
Fuzhi...
And you, bastard.
Had I known better
and sliced you into pieces
that day at Bofeng,
I wouldn't be suffering your stench now.
I'm the heir to my family estate.
You should be shedding
tears in ecstasy now.
Ungrateful woman!
Guards. Stop her!
Let me go.
Now!
Now come and be a lamb.
Fuzhi.
Today is our wedding day.
It's too late to back out now.
Father.
Father!
Forgive this display, everyone.
Let me go, bastards.
Father.
Mother.
I shall take Fuzhi home now.
Go on, then.
- Move!
- See yourself out.
Father...
Stop right there!
No one
is taking her away.
Fuzhi.
Sorry I am late.
Governor Wang.
To what do we owe the pleasure?
We're in the middle of my daughter's wedding.
Just how big
your mess is
to cross Lord Shen!
Ever heard of the famed Ear-Pimp,
the son of the Grand Tutor?
You're pitting yourself
against His Majesty's favorite.
I... I...
I had no idea.
No idea?
Any idea, then,
how miserable your life will look like
after you force my betrothed
to marry another man?
Lord Shen.
I'm befuddled...
Turns out
it's a family matter for Lord Shen.
Guards.
Your Lordship.
Tell these pieces of trash
to get out of here.
Yes.
Get a move on.
Move!
Mr. Song.
See yourself out.
I take my leave.
Lord Shen.
We haven't discussed this match
with your parents yet.
Sir.
Fuzhi and I are of one heart.
We've pledged ourselves to each other,
and we have lain together.
Lain together?
This is my fault.
I was a wastrel before.
Fuzhi had her doubts.
But I swear,
since I met Fuzhi,
there has been no other in my heart.
I meant to come with betrothal gifts
on an auspicious day.
But before I could,
Fuzhi was back to Shazhou.
If I hadn't made it here,
she'd already be
a Song bride, wouldn't she?
Lord Shen.
Had I known
you and Fuzhi were so deeply in love,
I'd tell the Songs to go fly a kite.
Tomorrow...
I will speak with the Songs tomorrow.
Tomorrow?
No, no, no, no.
Actually, I'm talking to them right now
to break off the engagement.
I'm returning the gifts, too.
At once.
In that case,
please rise, my father-in-law.
Thank you.
Lord Shen.
We're just
a household of merchants.
And Fuzhi
has little learning
and a stubborn nature.
In birth, beauty, and learning,
she cannot match you in any way.
When you say you love her,
surely you don't mean it?
Indeed.
Madam, this is both
an insult to Fuzhi,
as well as to my heart.
Fuzhi is my once in a lifetime.
Birth,
beauty,
learning...
None outweighs her.
My feelings
are no passing fancy,
and I swear it on my life.
If that is so,
why don't you
tie the knot tonight?
- Never.
- Great.
Madam, are you asking me
to
marry into your family?
Why, no!
I only fear that when
the heat of the moment fades,
Fuzhi would be left unwanted.
If we are to wed,
the six rites must each be observed,
and the three letters in order.
On the auspicious day,
I will come with a sedan of eight bearers
and
take her home in full glory.
It is Fuzhi's blessing
to have caught your eye.
My wife is ignorant.
Pray forgive her, Lord Shen.
Clueless!
Apologize to Lord Shen at once.
Apologies, Your Lordship.
It is getting late.
I will have the servants
prepare a guest room
for you to rest early.
My lord.
Since Lord Shen and Fuzhi
have already lain together,
what harm is there
in sharing a bed?
Madam, I...
You have been apart for days.
Surely you have
much to catch up on.
Xi'er.
Escort Fuzhi and Lord Shen to their room.
Now.
My lady.
How did this...
Lady Meng.
His Majesty grants you a carriage.
You may ride
everywhere you go.
After you, My Lady.
Tell His Majesty
I am grateful for his favor.
I haven't
walked the streets for a while.
I feel like taking a walk,
buying a few things I need.
My Lady.
The Emperor's word is law.
But rumors are wind.
If I got carried away,
I'd be playing
right into their hands.
I
have nothing to hide.
My conscience is clear.
Commander.
Convey that to His Majesty.
He won't hold it against you.
The rain won't stop.
We're not having customers.
Guess we'll have to queue up
and live off raindrops.
Is that not Lady Meng?
After what happened,
she's still showing her feathers?
Do you think she knows
how notorious she is now?
Madam.
You know what?
Lady Meng
is a real beauty.
That's all you've got?
A vixen
is born with
her seductive tricks.
Have you heard?
Someone saw her the other night,
luring those
two brutes in, before
bringing lightning
down upon one of them.
And then crack,
the man was
struck dead on the spot.
Then she...
She can't really have sorcery, can she?
Who knows?
Lately,
this endless rain
is supposedly her doing, too.
They say she beguiles all,
a portent of great calamity.
Good day, Lady Meng.
Stop staring. Keep away.
You don't want
to yourself jinxed.
Let's bail.
It's raining all the time.
It's such a nuisance to step out.
My hem is soaked.
The day after next is my birthday.
Such ill luck.
Bear with it, Wen.
The rouge from Golden Glow
is the finest in the capital.
You'll need it for your birthday feast.
Isn't that Meng Tinghui?
What is she doing out?
She's right at home in the rain, huh?
She surely should.
She's got nothing to lose now.
Look at her get-up.
"Nasty" written all over it.
Can't believe she's still out strutting,
when her name is mud.
Funny how some literally
think a dab of rouge
can turn a sparrow into a phoenix.
In terms of beauty,
she is
not a patch on Wen.
How's a woman in office any different?
Making a good match is true skill.
Indeed.
Anyone here?
This rouge is a delight.
I will take the whole batch.
Ladies, you are of noble birth.
Such sharp tongues
do not befit your station.
The crime lies with the perpetrator,
not the victim.
I won't have anyone
reveling in another's pain,
twisting right and wrong,
or spreading lies anymore.
Well said.
All this "paint and silk
making a person" stuff
is such folly.
Birth doesn't make a hero.
Marriage doesn't define success.
That's a narrow way to see the world.
You can't speak of ice to a summer insect.
Don't waste your breath on them.
I will not
use the same as they do.
I am not buying.
Zhili.
Miss Situ.
I'm grateful for your help.
Don't mention it, Lady Meng.
It was nothing.
The rain
won't let up for a while.
My Huiyin Studio is nearby.
We offer sound therapy.
Might I have the honour
of your company?
I have heard much of it.
The honour is mine.
My brother has spoken of it, too.
I must see it.
Please.
- I...
You go fir...
No, you first.
Still nervous?
W-Why would I?
Well, then, would you mind...
Ah,
it is as if...
the sky has a hole in it.
It's been leaking since forever.
The entire realm
is drenched in this downpour.
If this keeps on,
life
will be hard for the people.
So...
what brings you to Shazhou?
His Majesty sent me on business.
Got nothing going on today.
I thought I should stop at Bofeng.
I saw Haitang blocked by several men,
with a letter in hand.
I intervened,
and only then did I learn
of your situation.
I had written a secret letter
and asked Haitang to seek help.
Apparently,
she's been tailed by my stepmother.
I owe you one today.
I can't even imagine...
You always seem carefree, bold,
overbearing, even.
I had no idea
you grew up in such a household.
Hey, it's just a
stubborn, grasping father,
and a stepmother with
the face of a fairy
and the heart of a snake.
And a little brat of a stepbrother.
That's what it is to be a woman.
Does it still hurt?
No.
I will be gentler.
You are, after all,
a lady from one of Shazhou's finest families.
For some,
marriage would be a fine choice.
Why are you so firmly against it?
What do you know?
I did go to Jingdu
to keep Tinghui company.
Still,
my own ambitions are just as important.
I love doing business.
They say
a woman is supposed
to be the angel in the house.
But I'll never be.
I will expand Bofeng House
across all of Great Ning.
I will carve out
a world of my own.
Even if I grow
interested into marriage,
I will find a kindred soul,
who loves me,
and whom I love back.
We will earn our living together,
travel alongside each other,
and live our life to the fullest.
Turns out...
I have never truly known you.
I'm tired.
After three days locked up,
I can finally sleep properly.
There... there is
only one bed here.
I... we...
I almost forgot.
You have to have it comfortable.
You take the bed.
I will sleep on the floor.
I am a man.
How can I let you
take the floor?
You take the bed.
I...
Fuzhi, still up?
I will get the door.
Why did you hit me?
You told me to act the part!
I told you to act,
not to lose yourself in it!
I... lost myself?
You closed your eyes!
I was helping you out!
If anyone's
getting the wrong idea, it's you.
I...
You flatter yourself.
I was afraid my stepmother would find out.
And you were using me as a shield!
I panicked!
My apologies.
Was that your first kiss?
Of course not.
Go ask around the capital.
Shen Zhishu has
never lacked for admirers.
The ladies of the capital
throw themselves at me.
I have always
walked among the flowers
and savoured every fragrance.
Then why are you blushing?
I'm not.
I...
Well...
The room is too warm!
If that's the case,
I'm not taking the fall for
that desperate kiss.
Who needs you to?
It was such a bad kiss.
I'll have forgotten it
when I wake up.
Splendid.
My stepmother
is suspicious.
So tonight
I may need to trouble you
to share the bed with me.
What...
Quiet.
You startled me.
This is getting on my nerves.
See the act through.
Help all the way.
I'm going to bed.
Don't get under the covers.
I...
I'm quite tired too.
Miss Yan?
Liangzhou has seen seven days of rain.
The city walls are flooding.
The dams in Qingzhou have burst,
flooding the farmlands.
Jizhou reports
starving refugees blocking the roads.
Issue my decree.
The Ministry of Works will prepare dredging tools
and distribute them as needed tonight.
The Ministry of War will send 30,000 guards
to clear the rivers and reinforce the embankments.
No time to lose.
The Ministry of Revenue
may conscript refugees for the work,
paying them wages,
and set up soup kitchens
so the elderly, women, and children
may have two bowls of gruel a day.
Yes.
Your Majesty! Your Majesty!
You must take care of yourself!
In such time of the day, in such weather,
you cannot keep on like this!
Huang Bo.
As a commander,
you should put His Majesty's health first.
Steward You.
I...
Look at this rain.
Will it pause
if I retire?
Will the dams in Qingzhou
burst any later
because it is night?
But I...
Huang Bo.
See to it.
Yes.
This rain
shows no sign
of stopping.
What are you doing?
Sorry...
I was caught off guard.
Do you know
I tossed and turned all night
before I finally slept?
You did not sleep at all?
Are you awake, Lord Shen?
Yes.
Just now I was outside
and heard quite a commotion in here.
I know it's just newly-weds being newly-weds.
But you should take it slow.
I have
prepared a tonic.
In it are
ginseng, antler, and cinnamon.
He does not need that.
Keep it for yourself.
Later, then.
I will take my leave.
Miss.
Letter from Jingdu.
It seems urgent.
Jingdu?
It is from Tinghui.
Tinghui is in trouble!
We leave at once.
Ride hard for the capital.
Yes.
Your Majesty.
This man has confessed.
He was sent by the Tiger Roar Gang.
Your Majesty.
Mercy.